<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on johnokeeffe</title>
    <link>http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on johnokeeffe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:09:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Power Automate: Handling JSON schema validation with Parse JSON</title>
      <link>http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/2021-11-24-power-automate-parse-json-validation-handling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 18:09:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/2021-11-24-power-automate-parse-json-validation-handling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Had a scenario recently when working on a project where I needed to check some required columns from a staging excel file before it was inserted into a master excel file. Now in this case it only was a small subset of the overall columns in the excel were actually needed for the process. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t want the whole process to fall over if only one row was missing so I used the some scopes, parse JSON and JSON schema magic to build the below solution to get around it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logic App: Basic XML to JSON Expression Conversion</title>
      <link>http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/2020-11-01-logic-app-basic-xml-json-conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 18:09:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://johnokeeffe.ie/posts/2020-11-01-logic-app-basic-xml-json-conversion/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Working with JSON data in logic apps is native and really is a plus for the PaaS solution. Working with XML is also relatively easy, even with xpaths but it is not native like JSON. When I came across the problem myself I found it much faster and easier taking the approach of simply converting to JSON as I was much more familiar with it.
Below is an overview of the approach I take when working with XML data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
